Narrator: Previously on
AMC's The Walking Dead...
RICK: What is this place?
DEANNA: This is the start of
sustainability, community.
FATHER GABRIEL: Rick, his group...
they're dangerous.
GLENN: Noah died because of you.
You tried to kill me.
(crying)
DARYL: Why?
MORGAN: Cause all
life is precious.
(screaming)
DEANNA: Do it.
(gun shot)
MORGAN: Rick?
- (gunshot)
- (people scream)
Morgan:
Rick?
미친 소리 같겠지만
Rick: I know this sounds insane,
여긴 미친 세상이고
but this is an insane world.
한 발 앞서 공격해야 하는
We have to come for them
before they come for us.
단순한 세상입니다
- It's that simple.
- (walkers snarling)
내일 여기서
모든 것이 시작될 것입니다
This is where
it all starts tomorrow.
토빈이 트럭에
들어가서
Tobin gets in the truck,
출구를 열어주면
우린 흩어질 거고
opens the exit and we're off.
토빈은 트럭에서 내려
He hops out, catches up
with his team at red
길 서쪽의 레드 지점에
가 있는 팀에 합류합니다
staying on the west
side of the road.
데릴은 오토바이를 타
Daryl gets on his bike--
저기 보여요?
- (rumbling)
- You see that?
(metal groaning)
열렸습니다
지금 시작해야 합니다
It's open!
We got to do this now!
지금 시작해야 해요
We're doing this now!
토빈 팀, 빨리 움직여요
Tobin's group, get moving, go!
- 준비가 안 됐어요
- Sasha! Abraham!
- No, Rick, we're not ready.
- 지금 갑니다
-
Abraham: Damn straight,
we'll do it live.
레드지점에서 합류해서
대릴을 지원해 줘요
You meet Daryl at red. Let him
take them through the gauntlet.
- 그럴게요
- 출발
- Yeah, we meet at red.
- Rick: Go!
- 릭, 트렉터 상점은
제가 맡을꼐요
- 누구랑 가지?
- Rick, I'll hit the tractor place.
- Okay, who else?
가서 처리해야 해요
We got to take them out
or they'll distract the horde.
- 나도 갈께요
- 안 돼요
- I'm here, let me help.
- No.
- 나도 갈껍니다
- 내 지시대로 해요
- I'm here!
- Do everything I say.
- 그럴께요
- 릭, 예행연습하러
온 거 잖아요
- I will. - Rick, this was supposed
to be a dry run.
- 데릴, 어서 준비해
- 나온다!
- Rick: Daryl, get ready.
- They're coming.
계획 숙지도
다 못했어요
Rick, we haven't even gone
through the whole plan.
우린 할 거니까
돌아가려면 돌아가요
You want to go back, go back.
We're finishing this.
토빈, 내가 신호하면
쏴요
Tobin, you hit it on my signal.
집 쪽으로 가고 있어서
어쩔 수가 없어요
They're heading for home.
We don't have a choice.
조명탄 준비해요
Get ready to hit the flares.
발사!
Now!
(engine starts)
(growling)
토빈, 트럭을 움직여
Rick:
Tobin, hit the truck!
(theme music playing)
Sync & corrections by honeybunny
www.addic7ed.com
당신 말이 틀렸어
You were wrong.
Ron.
(door slams)
Thank you.
Of course.
Okay.
(groaning)
Glenn.
글렌 무슨 일이야?
괜찮아?
Glenn, what happened?
Are you okay?
괜찮아요
I'm okay.
꼴이 말이 아니네요
You guys look like shit.
타라는 괜찮아요
She's fine. She's fine.
She's okay.
타라?
Tara?
난 괜찮아
I'm okay.
글렌한테 가 봐요
You just check on them.
- 난 괜찮아
- 무슨 일이야?
- I'm okay.
- What happened?
밖에 나갔다가
We were out there.
좀비들을 만났는데
이제 괜찮아
The walkers and--
we're all right.
총알이 튀어서
맞았어
Got winged by a ricochet.
(groans)
괜찮아
It's all right.
살아났네
Holy shit.
다행이에요
Thank God...
머리가 그대로네요
nothing happened to your hair.
(chuckles)
유진 때문에
좀 무서운데
Okay, Eugene's freaking me out.
누가 노아 좀 불러 줄래요?
Somebody want to send Noah
in here to protect me?
당신 말이 맞았어요
You were right.
끝난 게 아니었어요
It wasn't over.
내일 다시 얘기 합시다
We should talk more tomorrow.
모건...
Listen...
에제 모험은 안 합니다
I don't take chances anymore.
안 하는 게 맞죠
And you shouldn't.
(ring clatters)
(snarling)
(gunshot)
다들 해야 할 일을
알거고
Rick on radio:
You all have your assignments.
만나는 지점도 알 겁니다
You know where to rendezvous.
데릴이 놈들을 유인하고
Daryl leads them out.
샤샤와 에이브라함이
Sasha and Abraham join him
at the bottom of the hill.
언덕길 끝에서 합류합니다
(flares fire)
글렌, 트렉터 상점을
Rick:
Glenn, you hit us
해결하면
합류하도록 해
when you take care of the
walkers at the tractor place.
거길 해결하는 게
급선무야
That's the one thing
we gotta get ahead of.
모두 냉정함을
유지해야 합니다
Everybody keep your heads.
정신 차립시다
Just keep up.
(walkers snarling)
(door opens)
괜찮대?
So, is he okay with it?
모건이 먼저
제안한거야
It was pretty much his idea.
상황을 잘 아니까
He gets it.
침대와 욕실은 있지만
It's got a bed and a bath,
그래도 감옥이야
but it's still a cage, you know?
모건은 이해할 거야
He gets it.
트럭에서 있었던 일은
얘기 들었어
He told me what happened
out there with the trucks.
'W'라는 놈들에 대해서도
He tell you about
those guys he met?
얘기하던가?
The Ws.
좀비 이마에
글씨를 새긴 놈들이지
Like that walker we saw, yeah.
전망대를 더 만들어야 해
We need more watch points.
디아나한테는 사람들을
모으지 말자고 할거야
And I'm gonna tell Deanna we don't
need to go looking for people anymore.
나랑 생각이 다른거야?
You feel different about it?
그래, 달라
Yeah, I do.
담장 밖의 사람들은
Well, people out there,
알아서 살아남으라고 해
they got to take care
of themselves,
우리도 마찬가지고
just like us.
곧 꺼내줄거야
I'm gonna get him out.
오랫동안 가두지는
않을거야
Shouldn't leave him in there
any longer than we have to.
괜찮은 거요?
You good?
네
Yeah.
애쓰고 있어요
I'm trying.
죽고 싶다는 생각을
계속하고 있다면...
Listen, if you're still looking to go
buck wild with the breath impaired...
질문에 대답한 것
같은데요
You already asked the question
and I already answered it.
그렇게 걱정하면서
왜 나선 거에요?
If you were so worried, why the hell
did you get into the car with me?
있잖아요...이렇게 엄청난 일을
해내는 거야말로
Listen, doing something
as big as this...
진짜 사는 거에요
that's living.
저기 있네요
There it is.
레드 지점에 도착했다
Sasha on radio: We're at red
at the bottom of the hill.
우리도 곧 도착한다
Daryl on radio: All right,
here comes the parade.
어디서 배운 겁니까?
Where'd you learn that?
친구한테서
A friend.
이전입니까?
이후입니까?
Before or after?
누가 질문하면
대답하는 게
I ask, you answer.
예의아닙니까?
It's common courtesy, right?
(chuckles)
이후였소
It was after.
일이 벌어진 후에
배웠죠
After everything.
이럴 수 밖에 없어서
미안합니다
Look, I'm sorry for this,
for having to do this.
괜찮아요
It's all right.
살아보니
The way I look at it,
출구가 없는 상황이
더 안전할 때도 있더군요
sometimes you're safer
when there's no way out.
다시 서로에 대해
알아가기로 합시다
Got to get to know
each other again.
처음이지만...
For the first time...
다시요
again.
(car approaches)
우리에요
- (car door opens, closes)
- Man: Hey, it's us.
안 열어줄겁니까?
We're back. You gonna
let us in or what?
문을 열 권한이 없으니까
안 열겁니다
I'm technically not authorized,
so I will not be doing so.
- 누굽니까?
- 먼저 말해요
- Who the hell are you?
- You first.
난 히스요
I'm Heath.
정찰 나갔다가
2주 만에 온 거요
I live here. My team's been on
a run the last couple weeks.
난 유진이요
I'm Eugene.
애런을 따라 들어온지
2주가 채 안 됐고
Aaron brought myself and my group
here directly within that window,
댁을 본 적이 없으니
확인이 불가능하군요
so we haven't had the chance to meet and
I can't exactly confirm your residence.
문 열어요
Open the gate.
날 죽이려 들지 않을 거란
보장이 있습니까?
If I do, how do I know
you won't attempt to kill me?
이봐요
난 죽이진 않을거에요
(chuckles)
Okay, look, I'm not gonna kill you.
하지만 계속 세워두면
But the longer you make me wait,
패 주고 싶을 것 같군요
the more you motivate me
to beat your ass, so...
(gate unlocks)
Thank you.
디아나가
보초 임무를 준 거요?
So Deanna put you on gate duty?
임무를 받은 건 아니고
원래 당번은 홀리에요
Oh, no, I'm not proper duty.
This is Holly's shift.
지나가는데
I was just walking by.
3초만 봐 달라길래
She asked if I could
relieve her for a few ticks.
싫다고 했는데
무시하고 가 버리더군요
I said, "No, thank you"
and she ignored me,
5초도 넘게 지났는데
which is obviously
what I should have done
안 돌아오네요
as it's been at least five
ticks and still no Holly.
(car door opens)
스캇입니다
이 쪽은 애니엥ㅅ
I'm Scott.
This is Annie.
반가워요
Hi.
Good to meet you.
일행이 몇 명이에요?
How many of you are there?
13명이요
13.
아니, 이젠 13명이네요
I mean, 12.
유감이에요
Annie:
I'm sorry.
내가 닫죠
I'll close up.
(gate squeaking)
(engine starts)
그동안 큰일이라도
있었나요?
Anything big happen
while we were gone?
어젯밤에
회의가 있었어요
Well, we had a meeting
last night.
(lock clangs)
내용은요?
Oh, yeah?
About what?
디아나를 만나서
직접 듣도록 해요
You might want
to talk to Deanna.
디아나 입으로요
Get it from the horse.
Her mouth.
알았죠?
You know?
알았어요
Right.
비슷한 사람을 만나니
좋군요
Hey, it's good to see
someone like me.
머리가 아주 근사해요
I fully respect the hair game.
- 담은 누가 세운 거요?
- 레지라는 남자가
- Who put up the wall?
- They did.
있었는데
There was a man, Reg.
그 사람이 설계하고
다 같이 만들었답니다
He drew up plans,
made it happen early on.
대부분 처음부터
A lot of people in here.
이 안에서 지냈다더군요
They've been inside
from the start.
식량과 전기를 공급받았고
존비는 별로 상대 안 해 봤죠
They had food, energy,
not a whole lot of walkers.
그냥 살아온거죠
They just lived.
살아남은게 아니에요
They haven't had to survive.
그걸 깨닫고
사람들을 받아들였는데
They figured that out,
brought us in.
너무 늦은 것 같아요
Still might be too late.
뭐가 늦었단 거요?
Too late how?
이 생활에 너무 젖었어요
For them to come around.
두고 봐야죠
We'll see.
디아나를 만나봐요
You'll have to talk to Deanna.
이 곳 책임자에요
She's the woman in charge.
레지가 디아나 남편이었죠
She was married to Reg.
죽은겁니까?
Was?
네
Yeah.
뭐하는 겁니까?
What are you doing?
다들...
We're--
돕고 싶어서요
I wanted to help.
하나만 파면 됩니다
We only need one.
시신이 둘이잖소
We have two men here.
살인자는 울타리안에
묻어 둘 수 없습니다
We're not gonna bury killers
inside these walls.
무슨 말인지는 알겠지만...
I understand how you feel.
I do.
당신이 결정할 일이 아니오
But it's not your decision.
토빈
Tobin.
릭이 맞아요
Rick's right.
밖으로 옮겨요
Take it away.
서쪽으로요
Go west.
브랜튼 가를 따라
몇 km를 가다가
Down Branton Road a few miles.
다리를 건너가요
Just past the bridge.
우린 그 쪽으로
안 다니니까요
We don't go out that way.
나무에 거름이라도 주라죠
Let the trees have him.
레지를 죽여서
내가 쐈습니다
I shot him
because he killed Reg.
어쩔 수가 없었어요
That was it.
We didn't have a choice.
감옥도 있잖소
You do have a cell.
살인자를 위한 곳은 아니죠
Not for killers.
나도 살인자요
I'm a killer, Rick.
당신도 마찬가지잖소
I am, and you are, too.
글렌, 도착했나?
Glenn, you there yet?
거의요, 확실히 처리하고
Glenn: Almost. We'll have it
handled before they get here.
옐로우 지점으로 갈께요
And we'll meet you at yellow.
알았다
Copy that.
막아줄겁니다
It'll hold.
다행이네요
Well, that's good.
뚫리면 우린
끝장이니까요
You know, considering
where we're standing.
미숀
Michonne.
예?
Yeah?
내 거처에 왔을 때 말이오
Back when you were
in that place...
거기서...
where I lived...
내 단백질 바를
가져갔나요?
did you take one
of my protein bars?
아뇨
No.
땅콩 버터도 분명히
하나 더 남아있었는데...
See, I could have sworn there was
one more peanut butter left.
늘 그런 기분이 들죠
(sighs)
That's how it is, isn't it?
땅콩 버터가 하나 더
남아 있었던 것 같은 기분요
You always think there's one
more peanut butter left.
(walkers growling)
(car approaching)
모건
Morgan.
여기 두고 갑시다
Maybe we just leave him here.
그런 사람이 아니잖소
That's not who you are.
당신을 알아요
I know.
잠깐만요
Hey.
모를 겁니다
You don't.
(distant walkers growling)
모건
Morgan.
그만해요
Stop.
못 들었어요?
Did you hear that?
(wind whistling)
(walkers growling)
(walkers snarling)
(grunts)
여긴 왜 온거냐, 론
What are you doing
out here, Ron?
아빠를 어디에 묻는지
확인하려구요
I wanted to know
where my dad was buried.
이것 때문이군요
Rick:
This is how.
뭐가요?
How what?
알렉산드리아가
안전한 이유 말입니다
How the community's still here.
가끔씩 좀비가
나타나긴 하지만
They've had walkers
at their walls,
대부분의 좀비는
but a lot of them,
maybe most of them,
여기 갇혀 있었던 겁니다
they wound up here.
론
Ron.
- 론
- 갈래요
- Ron.
- I'm going back.
- 기다려
- 전 괜찮아요
- Hey.
- I'm fine.
밖에 나오면 안 돼
You shouldn't be out here.
그건 아저씨 생각이죠
I don't care what you think.
생각이 아니라
확실히 아는 거야
It's not what I think,
it's what I know.
곧 너도 배우게 되겠지만
You can't protect yourself.
I'll show you how,
지금은 스스로를 지킬 수 없어
but right now you have
no idea what you're doing.
그런 상태로 밖에 나오면
죽는 거야
And if you come out here,
you're gonna die.
금방 죽지도 않고
끝나지도 않아
And it won't be quick
and it won't ever be over
너도 좀비가
'cause you'll be one of them.
될 테니까
That's what's gonna happen.
우리랑 같이 돌아가자
You're coming back with us now.
힘든 상황을 만들지 마
Don't make it hard.
글렌, 서둘러
Rick on radio:
Glenn, you have to hurry.
The noise could distract
the herd right off the road.
- 나에게 맡겨
- 우린 여기 있어
- Talk to me.
- Glenn: We're here.
(growling, banging)
엄청 많은 것 같은데
Nicholas:
Sounds like a lot.
(growling, banging)
- 조용히 처리해야 해요
- 어쩔 셈이에요
- We need it quiet.
- So what's the plan?
몇 놈씩 나오게
만들어야죠
Take 'em out a few at a time.
니콜라스, 문을 맡아요
Nicholas, you're at the door.
네
All right.
한 두놈이 나오면
문을 닫아요
You let one or two out
and then you close it.
계속 그렇게 하는 겁니다
You keep doing that. That's the trick.
That's how we control it.
- 히스
- 못 닫으면요?
- Heath--
- Wait, what if he can't close it?
- 할 수 있어
- 그럼 싸워야죠
- I'll be able to.
- Then we take them on.
싸운다구요?
We take them on?
문제가 생기면
If we get into trouble,
we go behind the building
건물 뒤 숲 쪽으로 유인해야 해
into the woods
and we draw them away.
자넨 못 봐서 모르겠지만
Hey, you've been out
on runs since he got here.
실력있는 사람이야
He knows what he's doing.
나랑 에이드리안은
한참 모자랐지
Me and Aiden, we didn't.
예행연습이었잖아
This was supposed to be
a dress rehearsal.
난 피자 배달원이었어요
I'm supposed to be
delivering pizzas, man.
데릴이 좀비 떼를
Daryl's leading them this way
이 쪽으로 몰아오고 있어요
and they're closing in.
이 소리 때문에
좀비 떼가
That noise is gonna pull
the herd right off the road
길에서 벗어나면
큰일이에요
and then we have
serious trouble.
우리가 해결해야 해요
We have to do this.
그래요, 합시다
Yeah, okay.
- 알았죠
- 그래요
- Okay?
- Okay.
- 알았죠
- 그래요
- Okay.
All right.
셋에 준비?
Glenn: On three. Ready?
하나..
One...
둘..
two...
셋...
three!
젠장
Shit!
(banging)
(growling, banging)
오래전에
Heath:
My team...
가본 곳입니다
we saw it early on,
초창기에 근처에
back when we were on
one of those first scouts,
뭐가 있나
정찰나갔다가 봤죠
finding out
what was around here.
아래 쪽에 캠프가 있는데
There was a camp at the bottom.
일이 벌어지기
시작할 때 쯤에
The people, they must have blocked
the exits with one of those trucks
트럭으로 막은 것 같더군요
back when everything
started to go bad.
모두가 존비가 돼 있었는대
They didn't make it.
They were all roamers.
10명 남짓 됐어요
Maybe a dozen of them.
이후로는 안 가봤나요?
No one's been back since?
DC라든가
DC,
물건이 있을 만한 마을은
전부 반대방향이고
every town worth scavenging are
all in the other direction.
몰락해버린 캠프 근처엔
가고 싶지 않았죠
And I never really felt like having a
picnic next to the camp that ate itself.
그 좀비 소리에
좀비들이 이끌려오고
So all the while the walkers
have been drawn by the sound
점점 더 많은 좀비들이
모여든 거군요
and they're making more sound
and they're drawing more in.
결국 이렇게 됐습니다
And here we are.
제가 제안한 방법이
위험하다고 생각하시겠지만
Now what I'm proposing,
I know it sounds risky,
하지만 이미 좀비들이
조금씩 나오고 있고
but walkers are already
slipping through the exits.
좀비들을 막고 있는
트럭 중 한 대는
One of the trucks
keeping the walkers in
곧 떨어질 상황입니다
could go off the edge
any day now.
폭우 한 번이면
끝장나겠죠
Maybe after one more hard rain.
그 통로가 열리면
놈들은 동쪽으로 향할 겁니다
That exit sends them east.
곧장 이 쪽으로 오겠죠
All of them.
Right at us.
통로가 열리는 건
This isn't about if
it gives, it's when.
시간문제입니다
반드시 열립니다
It's gonna happen.
그러니 빨리 해결해야겠죠
That's why we have
to do this soon.
정말이지..
끔찍하다는 말 밖에는
This is-- I don't even
have another word for it.
안나오네요
This is terrifying.
너무 위험해요
All of it.
하지만 다른 방법은
없는 거잖아요
But it doesn't sound like
there's any other way.
있을 수도 있어요
Maybe there is.
담장을 더 단단히 세우면
어떨까요?
I mean, couldn't we just
build up the weak spots?
제가 할 수 있어요
I could draw up plans.
레지랑 같이 일했었거든요
I worked on the wall with Reg.
건설팀이 합심하면
Construction crew--
단단하게 만들 수 있어요
we can try and make it safe.
그게 가능하다고 해도
저놈들 소리에
Even if we could,
the sound of those walkers
더 몰려들탠데
is drawing more
and more every day.
그건 막을 수 없어요
Building up the exits
won't change that.
릭 말대로 합시다
Deanna: We're gonna
do what Rick says,
릭이 짠 계획대로 해요
the plan he's laid out.
말했다시피
대릴이 좀비 떼를 몰고갈 겁니다
I told you all, we're gonna
have Daryl leading them away.
나도 갈께요
Sasha:
Me, too.
차를 몰고
같이 갈꼐요
I'll take a car,
ride next to him.
혼자서는 힘들어요
Can't just be him.
차와 오토바이가 함께하면
흐트러지지 않을 거에요
I'll keep 'em coming, Daryl
keeps 'em from getting sloppy.
나도 가겠소
I'll go with her.
혼자 가기엔
먼 길이니까요
It's a long way
to white-knuckle it solo.
두 팀이 필요합니다
We'll have two teams.
숲 양쪽에서
이탈이 없도록 해야 해요
One on each side of the forest
helping manage this thing.
망루에서 보초도
서야 하니까
We're gonna have a few
people on watch from now on.
로지타, 스펜서,
Rosita, Spencer, and Holly.
홀리는 여기 남아요
So they're out.
합류할 분 있습니까?
So who's in?
나요
Me.
다이나를 잘 지켜봐
You should keep an eye on her.
지난 번에 말했던 대로 해
Keep going with the plans
you talked about.
이건 중요한 일이잖아
Maggie: I know, but
this is important.
다이나도 중요해
She's important.
다들 겁먹었어
People are scared.
다이나가 정신차려야 해
They need to see her come back.
그것 때문만은 아니지?
That's not the only reason.
그래
Yeah, it isn't.
알았어
Okay.
저도 갈께요
I'm in.
나도 돕고 싶습니다
I'd like to help as well.
안됩니다
또 없습니까?
No.
Who else?
더 필요합니다
We need more.
다른 방법이 있을 겁니다
Carter: There's got
to be another play.
그렇게 많은 좀비를
어떻게 통제합니까?
We can't just control that many.
말했잖아요
좀비는 뭔가에
I said it before,
walkers herd up.
이끌리면 뗴를 지어
따라다니니까
They'll follow a path
if something's drawing them.
그걸 이용해야 합니다
That's how we can
get 'em all at once.
당신 말이라면
다 믿어야 하는거요?
So, what? We're supposed to
just take your word for it?
그런 일을 겪고도
당신을 따르라는 겁니까?
We're all supposed to just fall
in line behind you after...
무슨 일 말이요?
After what?
우리에게
총을 겨눴잖아요
After you wave a gun around
소리 질러대며
총을 겨눴어요
screaming,
pointing it at people.
그러다가 사람을 쐈고
After you shoot
a man in the face.
- 그걸로 모자라
- 그만해요!
- After you--
- Enough!
저도 갈께요
I'll do it.
저도요
Me, too.
뭐든 시켜요
나도 갑니다
Whatever you need, I'm in.
또 없어요?
Deanna:
Now who else?
저요
I'll go.
해애돼는 일이잖아요
나도 도울래요
We have to do this.
I need to help.
할 수 있겠소?
You sure you can handle it?
사람이 모자라잖아요
You need people.
꼭 해낼 겁니다
We'll make this work.
We'll keep this place safe.
이 곳을 지키고
가족을 지킬 겁니다
Keep our families safe.
We will.
그 계획,
다시 들읍시다
The plan.
Go through it again.
다 얘기 했잖아요
Man, he just said it.
하나 하나 다시 얘기해요
Every part again.
정확하게요
The exact plan.
(walkers growling)
(engine revving)
마샬가와 레딩 가의 교차로
Marshall and Redding.
- 이 곳에서 서쪽으로 몰 겁니다
- 어떻게?
- We force them west here.
- Deanna: How?
길을 막아서
서쪽으로 가게 할 겁니다
We block it off so they
can only go one way,
마을과 반대방향으로요
west, away from the community.
뭐로 막을 겁니까?
Carter:
Block it off with what?
차를 쓸 겁니다
Cars.
RV 차량과 트럭을
We'll use the RVs,
some of the bigger trucks,
길게 세울 겁니다
park them end to end.
앞에서 유인할 거니까
We'll be drawing them away.
- 계속 움직일 거에요
- 그 많은 좀비들이
- They're gonna keep moving.
- Carter: Yeah, but that many?
차에 막혀 돌아간다고?
Just bouncing off some sedans?
몇 놈이 차 사이로 들어오고
And then when they start
slipping through
뒤를 따르는 놈들이 생겨서
and the ones that walk away
start distracting the rest
유인이 안되면 어쩔 겁니까?
and you stop drawing them away?
일리있는 질문이에요
Man's got a point.
칠판을 쓰면 돼요
Eugene:
We got plates.
건설 현장에서 쓰던
큰 철판이요
The big-ass metal ones
from the construction site.
그걸로 벽을 세워서
We can use them
to fortify the whip wall.
충격을 흡수하고
It'd help disperse
the force of impact
방향을 바꾸는 겁니다
and direct the walkers clean.
당구대처럼요
Like a pool table.
Eight ball, corner pocket.
숫자가 너무 많아요
That's an army out there.
벽이 못 버티면
어쩔 겁니까?
And what happens
when this doesn't hold?
벽을 밀고 지나가면
이 굽은 도로를 타고
And they push on through.
The curve in this hillside
마을쪽으로
is gonna send them
right back east.
곧장 올 겁니다
Right back here.
그런 위험을
감수하겠다는 겁니까?
You seriously want to risk that?
아니죠
No.
벽이 버티도록
당신이 도와야 합니다
So you need to help us
to make it hold.
이 곳 담장을
함께 세웠잖소
These walls, you built them.
이미 대단한 일을
해냈어요
So you've already
done the impossible.
카터
Carter.
부탁이에요
Please.
- (engine roaring)
- (walkers snarling)
(metal rattling)
(rattling continues)
(snarls)
(chatter)
우리가 살 길을
찾아야 한다고 했지
Hey, what you said before about us
needing to take care of ourselves?
사람들을 더 모으는 게
Going out finding more people,
우리가 살 길이야
that is taking care
of ourselves.
결정은 네 몫이야
Your call, though.
고마워
Thanks.
나도 같이 갈 수 있어요
You know, I can come
with all of you.
총쏘는 법도 배웠잖아요
You and Daryl have been
teaching me how to shoot.
그럭저럭 잘 쏘더군요
(sighs)
I think you got the hang of it.
여기 남아있어요
Rick:
You should stay back,
사람들의 분위기를
읽어줘요
get a feel for how
people feel now.
오랫동안 함꼐
지내야 할테니까요
We still got a long way
to go with them.
잘 될 거에요
We'll get there.
책임자는 다이나지만...
She's in charge.
이젠 당신이 이끄는 거에요
But you're in charge now.
(banging)
- 너무 위험해요
- 유일한 방법입니다
- This is a bad idea.
- This is the only idea.
열두 놈 정도
있는 것 같아요
I think there's something
like a dozen in there.
각자 다른 방향에서
놈들을 유인해요
We stay back, we get on opposite
ends, we draw them to each of us.
- 네 놈씩 맡을까요?
- 아뇨
- Try and take down four each?
- No.
나랑 히스가 맡을 거에요
This is just me and Heath.
당신은 뒤로 물러나 있어요
You get back and you stay back.
일이 잘 못되면
릭한테 전하고 놈들을 유인해요
Things go south, you tell
Rick and you draw them away.
물러서라니까요
Just move back.
저 사람 때문에
노아가 죽었다고요?
He got Noah killed?
그래요
He did.
그 뿐이 아니에요
He did more than that.
글렌을 숲으로 유인해서
죽이려고 했어요
He lured Glenn into the woods
and tried to kill him.
정말이에요?
What the hell?
- 그래요
- 정말요?
- Yeah.
- What?
글렌은 말하고 싶으면
모두에게 말해요
Glenn told me I could tell everyone
if that's what I wanted to do.
니콜라스를 추방하면
Could get Nicholas exiled.
밖에 나가서 죽겠죠
He'd die out there.
하지만 알리지 않았어요
Could have done that.
당신도 원하는 대로 해요
You could do that now.
노아를 죽이고
글렌을 죽이려 했다면서요
He got Noah killed
and he tried to kill Glenn?
글렌은 사람들을
돕고 싶어해요
Glenn saves people.
저런 인간까지도요
Even people like that.
나도 용납할 수 없었지만
I couldn't accept it either.
당신이 생각나더군요
But then I thought about you.
내 생애 최악의 날에
How we were on different
sides of that fence
우린 적이었는데
on the worst day of my life.
지금은 내게 가장 중요한
사람 중 하나가 됐어요
And now you're one of the most
important people in the world to me.
달라질 수 있어요
Things can get better.
달라지게 만들 수 있죠
We can make them better.
어떻게 하고 싶어요?
You tell me what you want to do.
(sniffles)
두 사람 생각에 따를께요
I'm just gonna follow
your lead, okay?
그래요
Okay.
미안해요
I'm sorry.
준비됐어요?
You ready?
준비는 안 됐지만
어자피 해야 하니까요
No. But since you're
doing this thing anyway...
좋아요
All right.
계속 오넹ㅅ
They're still coming.
(gun clicks)
(walker snarling)
됐어요
Get it.
(grunts)
잘했어요
Glenn:
Good.
갑시다
Let's go.
이거 드세요
Here you go.
감사합니다
Oh, thank you.
캐롤 맞죠?
It's Carol, right?
네
Yeah.
릭과 오랫동안 지냈나요?
You been with Rick long?
애틀란타에서부터요
Since Atlanta.
경찰이세요?
And were you a cop, too?
왜 그렇게 생각해요?
Why would you think that?
늘 지켜보고 있더군요
You're always watching.
항상...
You always...
준비가 돼 있어요
seem ready.
무슨 준비요?
For what?
해결할 준비 말입니다
You know, to handle things.
친절한 분이시네요
Aren't you sweet?
(snarling)
뭐죠?
What is it?
산책이라도 하려는지
몇 놈이 이탈했어요
Got some looky-loos taking a little
constitutional off the shoulder.
뒤 따르는 놈들이 많아요
They starting a damn walkout.
데릴한테 맡으라고 할까요?
You want to have Daryl
circle back?
아뇨
No.
금방 따라 올테니
계속가요
Keep moving.
I'll catch up.
에이브러험
Abraham.
멍청한 인간
Idiot.
(shouting)
이리와
Abraham:
Come on!
어디 따라와 봐라
This is my ride, asshole.
Whoo!
엉망이군
(chuckles) Well, look at me.
레지가 칼에 맞던날
You didn't see Reg
그 자리에 없었죠?
the night he got it.
엄청났어요
That was a mess.
피트는
And Pete.
머리통이..
His face just...
폼페이처럼
터져버렸는데
blowing up like Pompeii
그 때 내가
바로 옆에 있었죠
right when we were
cheek to cheek.
아직도 귓 속에 피트의
살덩어리가 있는 것 같아요
I still think I got some
of his brains in my ear.
(laughs)
어디 보자
Well, look at that.
됐군요
All right.
문제는 싹
해결된 것 같아요
Everything is aces again.
왜 이러는 거죠?
What the hell are you doing?
세상에 맞서는 거 잖아요
I'm just grabbing
the bull by the nutsack.
이런 게 사는 거죠
I'm living, darling,
당신 말 대로요
just like you.
(laughing)
제대로 인사를 못했군요
I haven't had a chance
to say it yet,
레지 일은 정말
유감입니다
but I'm sorry about Reg.
현명하고 친절한
분이셨는데
He was smart and kind.
좋은 분이셨죠
He was a good man.
옳은 결정을 하신 겁니다
필요한 일이에요
It was the right call.
We need this.
또 뭐가 필요하죠?
What else?
애기해 줘요
You need to tell me.
마을 사람들 모두가
무장해야 합니다
People need to be armed
inside the walls.
한 명도 빠짐없이
훈련해야 하죠
They need to be trained,
everyone.
- (twigs snap)
- (banging)
가만히 계세요
Stop.
놈들이 옵니다
Here they come.
카터, 뒤를 봐요
Carter, heads up.
- 기다려요
- Hey.
- Man: Wait, folks.
삽으로 쳐요
총을 쏘면 더 몰려들겁니다
Use your shovels.
The guns will draw more.
도와줘요
Help us.
할 수 있습니다
할 수 있어야 해요
You can do this.
You need to, all of you.
모건, 안 돼요
Rick:
Morgan, don't!
모험은 안한다고
했잖소
You said you don't
take chances anymore.
시간이 없어요
Carter:
Time is running out.
내일 예행연습을 한다니까
그 때가 기회에요
He's talking about a dry run tomorrow.
That's it.
릭이 피트를 막았어요
Olivia: Rick stopped Pete.
He stopped him.
아내를 때린다고 죽입니까?
Carter: This is not
taking out a wife-beater.
카터, 피터는 사람을 죽였어
Tobin:
He was a murderer, Carter.
릭의 계획은
자살행위나 마찬가지야
Carter: What Rick wants
to do is suicide.
스펜서에겐 미안하지만
디아나는 제정신이 아니야
I'm sorry, Spencer, but Deanna
is asleep at the wheel.
우리가 해결해야 해
우리가 막아야 한다고
So it's on us.
We have got to stop him.
그 신부 말이 맞았어
What the priest said about
him, about these people,
그 인간들을 믿으면 안 돼
he was right.
얼마나 더 죽어 나가야
How many more of us have to die
움직일거지?
before we do something?
더 기다리면 늦어
'Cause pretty soon
it's gonna be too late.
카터, 이건 보통일이 아니에요
Olivia: Carter, you need
to be really careful here.
디아나에게
이런 얘기를 하려면...
You're talking about us going
to Deanna and telling her--
얘기하자는 게 아니에요
Carter: No, I'm not talking
about talking some more.
회의를 하자는 것도 아닙니다
About meetings.
I'm not talking about that.
우리가 먼저
죽여야 합니다
Plain and simple, we kill him
놈이 우릴 죽이기 전에요
before he kills us.
(shatters)
(clatters)
안녕하세요
Hello.
카터
Tobin:
Carter.
- 다 들었어
- 못 들었어요
- He heard.
- I didn't.
- 그게..
- 카터
- I mean, I didn't--
- Tobin: Carter.
다 들었어
He heard.
(hammer clicks)
안 돼요
그러면 안 돼요
Olivia: Carter, don't.
You can't.
(door opens)
이게 무슨 일이죠?
What the hell is going on?
뭐하는 겁니까?
What are you doing?
당신한테서
여길 되찾으려는 거요
I'm taking this place
back from you.
그런 얘길
나누고 있었습니까?
That's what you were
talking about in here?
카터가 한 얘깁니다
That's what he
was talking about.
전망대를
세울 걸 그랬어요
See, I would have-- I would
have set up some lookouts.
그랬으면 좋았을텐데
That would have been
the smart thing.
그랬으면 그렇게...
You know,
if I happened to--
- (groans)
- (hammer clicks)
우리한테서 이 곳을
뺴앗을 수 있을 것 같소
You really think you're gonna
take this community from us?
글렌과 미숀과
From Glenn?
From Michonne?
대릴과 내게서?
From Daryl?
From me?
내가 누군지 알고
얘기하는 겁니까?
Do you have any idea
who you're talking to?
- 나 혼자 그런 거요
- 뭐요?
- It was just me.
- What?
나 혼자 생각한 거니까
It was--
it was just me.
나만 죽여요
Just-- just kill me.
릭
Rick.
괜찮아요
I'm good.
걱정하지 마요
모두 힘을 합쳐야 합니다
You can try to work with us.
그래야 살아남는 겁니다
You can try to survive.
할 수 있겠소?
Would you do that?
(snarling)
(whistles)
성공이군요
It's working.
당신 말이 맞았어요
You were right.
여러분, 완벽하게 끝내야 합니다
Everyone, we need
to finish this.
앞 뒤로 흩어져서
놈들을 지켜야 합니다
We have to keep moving and fan out
down that thing front to back.
퍼레이드의 경찰처럼
하는 겁니다
Like we said, cops at a parade.
글렌, 무전기가 있으니까
Glenn, you take the back.
- 뒤 쪽을 맡아
- 네
- You got the other walkie.
- Got it.
흐트러지면 앞쪽에서
총을 쏴서 주의를
If it gets sloppy,
we fire our weapons,
끌어야 합니다
pull them back on track.
- 앞을 맡을께요
- 간격을 두고 따라 갑시다
- I'll hit the front.
- Okay, one after the other.
(snarling)
- (snarling)
- (gasps)
(screaming)
(screaming continues)
토빈, 놈들이 이탈합니다
Tobin, they're breaking off.
어떻게 할까요?
Tobin: What do you
want us to do?
총을 쏴서 유인해요
Fire your guns
and draw them back.
(Judith coughs)
날씨가 좋군요
It's nice out.
그러게요
Yeah.
미안해요
Hope you don't mind.
한가로운 시간을
즐기고 싶은데
I wanted to enjoy
the evening a little
저긴 이런 공간이
없어서요
and I don't have a porch
over there, so...
짐 챙겨요
Get your stuff.
여기서 우리랑
지냅시다
You should stay
with us over here.
좁지 않나요?
Morgan:
You got room?
공간은 만들면 돼요
Rick:
We'll make it.
이젠 저기서
지내지 않아도 돼요
We don't need
to do that anymore.
난 당신을 압니다
I know you, Morgan.
처음 만난 거나
마찬가지지만 말이죠
Even if this is the first time.
안아볼래요?
You want to hold her?
(chuckles)
좋아요
Okay.
모건 아저씨란다
- This is Morgan.
- (Judith coos)
아빠 친구야
He's a friend of mine.
Hey.
안녕
Hi.
Okay.
참 예쁘구나
Let me have a look at you.
Hey, hey.
카터라는 사람을
해치지 않았던 거
You with that man Carter,
in the armory--
그게 바로 당신이오
that's you.
킹 카운티에서 만났을 때
You're still the same man
I met in King County.
끝나지 않았다고
말했던
The one that came back
and told me it wasn't over.
바로 그 사람 말이오
That was you.
지금 내 앞에 있는
바로 당신 말입니다
Same you that's right in
front of me right now.
죽이고 싶었어요
I wanted to kill him.
그 편이 편하니까요
So it would be easier.
그럼 걱정거리 하나는
So I wouldn't have to worry
덜 테니까요
about how he could screw up
또 멍청한 짓을 해서
일을 망칠지
or what stupid thing he'd do
next because that's who he is.
요
그런 사람은 그런 사람이에요
Just somebody who
shouldn't be alive now.
(sighs)
죽이고 싶었어요
I wanted to kill him.
그런데 그 순간
But all that hit me and...
그럴 필요가 없다는 걸
깨달았죠
I realized
I didn't have to do it.
그 사람은
상황 파악을 못해요
He doesn't get it.
그런 사람은
Somebody like that...
결국은 다 죽을 겁니다
they're gonna die
no matter what.
(screaming)
(screaming continues)
죽을 것 같아
Oh, I'm dead.
카터, 심호흡 해 봐요
- Carter, take a breath.
- (screaming continues)
카터
Carter.
- 안 돼
- 조용히 해요
- Oh, God! (screaming)
- Be quiet. Shh.
카터, 카터
- Oh, God.
- Carter. Carter, shh.
조용히 하라니까요
- (screaming)
- You got to be quiet.
- Shh.
(screaming stops)
(distant gunfire)
효과가 있습니다
Tobin on radio:
It's working.
총소리에 돌아오고 있어요
The gunfire is bringing them
back on the road.
(gunfire continues)
- 계속 가요, 토빈
- 네
- Rick: You got them, Tobin.
- Tobin: Copy that.
비명은 뭠니까?
What was that screaming?
카터가 얼굴을 물렸는데
That was Carter.
내가 조용히
He got bit right in the face.
시켰어요
I stopped him.
그린 지점까지 가서
데릴 일행한테 넘기려면
We have a good hour until
we have 'em to green
한 시간은 족히 걸립니다
when we hand them off to
Daryl, Sasha, and Abraham.
집으로 돌아가서
상황을 알려 주겠습니까?
Why don't you head back, tell
everyone what's happening?
알았소, 그런데
- They should know.
- Okay, Rick, I just--
그렇게 해 줘요
Will you do that for me?
난 저걸 처리하죠
I'll take care of that one.
미숀, 모건의 자리를 맡아요
Michonne, you take point.
이런 세상이란 거 잘 압니다
I know it's how it is.
알아요
I do.
그래요
Yeah.
나도 알아요
I do, too.
(snarling)
(door opens)
안녕하세요
Rick:
Hey.
내일 예행연습 때
쓸 조명탄을 가지러 왔어요
I was just getting
more flares for tomorrow.
내가...
I know I haven't--
당분간은
지금 이대로
I just-- I just thought
it might be best
내버려두는 편이
나을 것 같더군요
if I let things be for a while.
론한테 들었어요
Ron told me what happened.
그 얘기도 하려고 했는데
Yeah, I wanted to talk
to you about that.
- 밖에 나가면 안 돼요
- 물론 안 돼죠
- He shouldn't have been out there.
- No, he shouldn't have.
맞는 말이에요
You're right.
하지만 당신은
론한테 그러면 안 돼요
But you can't talk
to him like that, Rick.
손도 대면 안돼요
You can't touch him.
당신은 안 돼요
Not you.
알아듣게 설명하려고
잡은 겁니다
Ron needed to hear
every word I said.
화가 나서 그런게 아니라
That's why I grabbed him.
I wasn't angry.
말해주려고 그런 거에요
I was just telling
him the truth.
당신 입에서 나오는 말은
절대 안 들을 거에요
If it's coming from you,
he can't hear it.
이해할 거라 생각해요
You got to understand that.
자기 몸을 지킬 줄
알아야 해요
He needs to know
how to handle himself.
- 내가 가르쳐 줄 겁니다
- 릭
- I can teach him. I can teach you.
- Rick.
- 당신도 배워야 해요
- 릭
- You need to know how.
- Rick.
이런 상황이 올 걸
예상하고
When I found out
we could have them,
로지타 한테 부탁했어요
I asked Rosita
to start showing me how.
로지타한테 배워서
Okay? She's gonna teach me
and I'm gonna teach Ron
론과 샘한테 가르칠 거에요
and I'm gonna teach Sam.
회의 때 당신이 한 얘기를
다 들었어요
I heard what you were saying
to us at the meeting.
그 전에 우리 집에서
한 얘기도요
And at my house
before, you know.
싸울 거에요
I am gonna fight, Rick.
(snarling)
마지막 그린지점입니다
All right,
this is the finish line.
우린 여기서 빠질 겁니다
When we make it to green,
we fall back.
양 옆이 강과 산이니
이탈은 안 할 겁니다
The ditches and ridges
will keep them on the road.
우리는 집으로 돌아가고
대릴, 사샤, 에이브라함은
We head home, but Daryl,
Sasha, and Abraham
30KM를 더 이동할 겁니다
take them the rest of
the way, 20 miles more.
갑시다
All right, let's go.
물어볼게 있습니다
Got a question for you.
함께 여행을 떠나기 전에
알아보고 싶은게 있어요
Just some intel before our
little road trip tomorrow.
물어봐요
Ask me.
죽고 싶어서
자진한 겁니까?
You doing this
'cause you want to die?
아뇨
No.
여길 지나가게 될 텐데
We're gonna take 'em
right past here.
저 소리에 좀비들이
이탈할 수도 있습니다
All that noise
could distract them.
돌아가는 길에
해결할 겁니다
We'll clear it on
our way back tonight.
내일 문제가
생기면 안되니까요
We don't want any
surprises tomorrow.
(snarling, banging)
당신이 한 짓에 대해선
Hey, what you've done,
지금은 반성만 하고 있어요
you're gonna sit
with it a while,
내일은 나오지 마요
'cause I don't want you
out here tomorrow.
준비가 안 됐어요
You're not ready.
곧 준비될 겁니다
You will be.
내가 도와줄 겁니다
Some time soon,
I'll make sure of it.
그 다음에 죗값을 치뤄요
And then you start
to make it right.
고마워요
Thank you.
(snarling)
미친소리 같겠지만
I know this sounds insane,
여긴 미친 세상이고
but this is an insane world.
한발 앞서 공격해야 하는
We have to come for them
before they come for us.
단순한 세상입니다
It's that simple.
(snarling)
(horn blaring)
무슨 일이에요?
What the hell is happening?
나팔소리 같은데요
It's a horn or something.
좀비 떼가
이탈하고 있어요
It's pulling the back
half off the road.
맙소사
Oh, God.
멀리서 나는 소리에요
Michonne: Whatever
that is, it's far.
집에 거의 다 도착했습니다
알렉산드리아, 분양합니다
- It sounds like it's coming from--
- Home.
(snarling)
(horn continues blaring)
Sync & corrections by honeybunny
www.addic7ed.com